Will Gallia

Contact wgallia@gmail.com http://wgallia.com +447944137483

EMPLOYMENT Polkima, Izmir

General Computer Programmer

05.2012 - 10.2012

Working at this fibreglass factory, I worked on various computing problem, such a programming a Comau industrial robot in the PDL2 domain specific language to trim tractor engine hoods. I also wrote a number of tools in Excel VBA to automate invoice generation, product verification and other accounting tasks.

Matt Watkins Design, London

iOS Programmer

05.2012 - 10.2012

I was the sole developer for Würfel-Mosaik, a digital version of the classic Swiss children's game of the same name. The iPhone/iPad application makes considerable use of iCloud, Core Graphics and social networking APIs.

Hellicar & Lewis, London

Interaction Designer

06.2012 - 08.2012

I worked in a team of three developers creating Triptych, a set of interactive installations showcasing Intel's new range of processors. Interaction was through a Microsoft Kinect sensor and large projections. The projects were programmed in C++ & GLSL and used openFrameworks. The project was open source.

greyworld, London

Computer Programmer

07.2010 - 09.2010

As a summer job, I programmed real-time generative visuals for London based art collective greyworld and advertising agency Ogilvy. The project was built with Processing.

Dursley Swimming Pool and Sports Centre, Gloucestershire

Lifeguard 07.2007 - 01.2008

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Goldsmiths College, London

Lab Assistant

01.2013 - 03.2013

I assisted in the 1st year BSc and MA programming labs, helping students learn Java in the Processing environment and C++ with openFrameworks.

Swanlea School, Whitechapel, London

Assistant Teacher

03.2011 - 04.2011

As part of the TDAs Student Associate scheme, I worked alongside teachers in both the Science and Maths departments, teaching students preparing for their GCSEs.

EDUCATION

Goldsmiths College, London

PhD Computational Arts & Technology

01.2014 - Present

Imperial College, London

MSc Computing - Visual Information Processing (Merit)

10.2012 - 09.2013

Dissertation: Neighbourbood Approximation Forest based Segmentation

Goldsmiths College, London

 $BSc\ Creative\ Computing\ (First\ w/\ Undergraduate\ Prize) \\ 09.2009\ -\ 05.2012$

 ${\bf Dissertation:}\ \ Construct:\ \ Voxel\ based\ visual\ hulls$

Clifton College, Bristol

Peter Brook (All Round) Scholarship 09.2002 - 06.2007

A-Level: Maths: A, Physics: A, Chemistry: B

GCSE: 4 A*, 5 A, 2 B

Skills Computer Programming

I have experience programming in a number environments and I am familiar with a range of tools. For realtime work I primarily work in C++, using OpenGL and possibly utilising libraries such as **openFrameworks** or **Cinder**. I am proficient in **Java** and intimately familiar with **Processing**. I have experience implementing machine learning and signal processing algorithms in **GNU Octave/MATLAB** and **Python**. For mobile applications i like to use iOS with **Objective-C**. I have also worked in the back and front end of the web domain, using languages such as **JavaScript**, **PHP** and technologies such as **MySQL** and **CouchDB**. I have an interest in embedded programming where I usually write firmware in **C**, though I frequently use the **Arduino** to prototype. I like to use **git**.

Interests Cycling: London \rightarrow Munich (solo), route: http::/where.is.wgallia.com

German: European Common Framework Level A2

Languages English & Turkish

References Dr. Daniel Rueckert, Tutor: d.rueckert@imperial.ac.uk

Dr. Mick Grierson, Tutor: m.grierson@gold.ac.uk

Matt Watkins: info@wurfelmosaik.com